(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.2",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
3D: March 26th, 2026 @studio. "DONT GET LOST AGAIN -kchan"
[Text: 3D: March 26th, 2026 @studio. "DONT GET LOST AGAIN -kchan"]
うーん……
Hmmm...
また迷った？
Am I lost again?
このドア、怪しいけど……
This door looks sus...
入る？
Should I enter?
それともやめとく？
Or should I not?
dahlah. まあ、いっか。
Dahlah. Well, whatever.
dahlah.
[Song: dahlah.]
Dahlah saja
Just let it be
Walk it off and go
Isn't this a thing that you're used to?
Disappointed and feeling blue
When the world doesn't go the way you want it to?
Oh oh
And maybe now is just the perfect time
To let it go and just unwind
There's no need to ask why ever again
Just let it go
The answer you've been looking for
No need to be sad about it just try to get through your day
Just let it go
Then maybe in the end you'll know
You got what it takes to get through the ache and still win the day
Dahlah saja Oh dahlah saja
Just let it be, oh just let it be
Walk it off and go
Dahlah saja Oh dahlah saja
Just let it be, oh just let it be
Walk it off and go
What else can you do?
When your feelings are barely there
Up to a point of pure despair
When you have given it your all but ends in vain
Just let it go
The answer you've been looking for
No need to be sad about it just try to get through your day
Just let it go
Then maybe in the end you'll know
You got what it takes to get through the ache and still win the day
Let life takes over the wheel
Let life take over the wheel
And shift it to higher gears
Then you will finally see
Just let it go
The answer you've been looking for
You don't need to be sad
You don't need to be mad
Just try to get through your day
Just let it go
Then maybe in the end you'll know
You got what it takes
To get through the ache
And still win the day
You got what it takes
To get through the ache
And still win the day
Dahlah saja
Just let it be
Oh, Dahlah saja
Oh, just let it be
Walk it off and go
Dahlah saja
Just let it be
Oh, Dahlah saja
Oh, just let it be
Walk it off and go
ma ii ka
Well, whatever
Podcast sendiri, ya?
A solo podcast, huh?
ソロポッドキャストってこと？
So it's a solo podcast?
Kaeloooo~!
Nani?
What?
なに？
Apaan, tuh?
What is that?
なにそれ？
Hmm...
9 lampu...
9 lights...
9つのライトがある......
There are nine lights...
Mic...
マイク......
headset...
ヘッドセット......
Content creator?
まさかコンテンツクリエイター......？
Could it be a content creator...?
Eh...
え......
Warnanya...?
The color...?
その色......？
That color...?
hololive ID!?
ホロライブID！？
Sahabat sejatiku
My true friend
Hilangkah dari ingatanmu
Have you disappeared from your memory
Di hari kita saling berbagi
On the day we share
Dengan kotak sejuta mimpi
With a box of a million dreams
Aku datang menghampirimu
I come to visit you
Kuperlihatkan semua hartaku
I show you all my treasures
Kita s'lalu berpendapat
We always have the opinion
Kita ini yang terhebat
That we are the greatest
Kesombongan di masa muda yang indah
The beautiful arrogance of youth
Aku raja kaupun raja
I am the king, you are the king too
Aku hitam kaupun hitam
I am black, you are black too
Arti teman lebih dari sekedar materi
The meaning of a friend is more than just material
Pegang pundakku, jangan pernah lepaskan
Hold my shoulder, never let it go
Bila ku mulai lelah?
If I start to get tired?
Lelah dan tak bersinar
Tired and not shining
Remas sayapku, jangan pernah lepaskan
Squeeze my wings, never let it go
Bila ku ingin terbang?
If I want to fly?
Terbang meninggalkanmu
Flying and leaving you
Ku s'lalu membanggakanmu
I always pride myself in you
Kaupun s'lalu menyanjungku
You always flatter me
Aku dan kamu darah abadi
You and I are eternal blood
Demi bermain bersama
For the sake of playing together
Kita duakan segalanya
We share everything
Merdeka kita, kita merdeka
We are independent, we are independent
Pegang pundakku, jangan pernah lepaskan
Hold my shoulder, never let it go
Bila ku mulai lelah?
If I start to get tired?
Lelah dan tak bersinar
Tired and not shining
Remas sayapku, jangan pernah lepaskan
Squeeze my wings, never let it go
Bila ku ingin terbang?
If I want to fly?
Terbang meninggalkanmu
Flying and leaving you
Tak pernah kita pikirkan
We never thought about
Ujung perjalanan ini
The end of this journey
Tak usah kita pikirkan
We don't need to think about it
Ujung perjalanan ini
The end of this journey
Dan tak usah kita pikirkan
And we don't need to think about it
Ujung perjalanan ini
The end of this journey
Happy Anniversary Tiga...
Happy 3rd Anniversary...
Abah, abah gimana?
Abah, what about Abah?
Okay, that's kind of an easy trick.
So that's how these rooms work, huh?
Berarti pintu ini juga dikunci, ya?
I guess this door is locked too, right?
Okay... I need to find a clue here and get out. Hmm...
Hmm...
[Title: Open This / Bukan Jebakan]
[Title: Open This / Not a trap]
[Title: Only For The Weak Ones / Hanya Untuk Yang Lemah]
[Title: Only For The Weak Ones / Only for the weak]
What am I supposed to do with this?
Coffee? Arrow? Right? What?
Masih ada satu kotak lagi sih, tapi aku kan bukan yang lemah, so...
There's still one more box, but I'm not the weak one, so...
Aku nggak paham. Lagian siapa yang bakal peduli kalau aku buka yang ini?
I have no idea. Besides, who's going to care if I open this one?
Aku harus buru-buru keluar dari tempat aneh ini,
I just need to get out from here and leave this weird place,
kalau nggak nanti lewat 3D showcase...
or else I'll be late for my 3D showcase...
Loncat! Jalan kiri!
Jump! Walk left!
Oke, ya udah sana.
Okay, fine then.
Satu, dua, tiga, loncat!
One, two, three, jump!
Jalan... kiri!
Walk... left!
Loncat! Jalan...
Jump! Walk...
Kanan! Nggak apa-apa lompat-lompat.
Right! It's okay to keep jumping.
Loncat! Kiri lagi!
Jump! Left again!
Loncat! Wah ini yang penting bisa ya.
Jump! The important thing is just to make it.
Kiri kiri kiri kiri!
Left, left, left, left!
Eh? Aku nggak ngerti...
Eh? I don't get it...
Oh! Kopi kanan!?
Oh! Copy right!?
Ya ampun...
Oh my...
Clue apaan coba...
What kind of clue is that...
Mentari terbenam
The sun sets
temani dalam kesendirianku
keeping me company in my loneliness
Temani aku dalam kepedihan ini
Keep me company in this pain
Ku bertahan
I will survive
Mentari terbenam
The sun sets
beri semangat baru tuk jiwaku
giving a new spirit to my soul
Beri kicauan merdu tuk hidupku ini
Giving a melodious chirp to my life
Ku bertahan
I will survive
Aku pasti bisa
I can definitely do it
Menikmati semua dan menghadapinya
Enjoy everything and face it
Aku yakin pasti bisa
I am sure I can do it
Mentari terbenam
The sun sets
beri semangat baru tuk jiwaku
giving a new spirit to my soul
Beri kicauan merdu tuk hidupku ini
Giving a melodious chirp to my life
Ku bertahan
I will survive
Aku pasti bisa
I can definitely do it
Menikmati semua dan menghadapinya
Enjoy everything and face it
Aku yakin pasti bisa
I am sure I can do it
Aku pasti bisa
I can definitely do it
Menikmati semua dan menghadapinya
Enjoy everything and face it
Aku yakin pasti bisa
I am sure I can do it
Aku ingin lepaskan seluruh bebanku
I want to release all my burdens
Dan ku jalani hidupku dengan senyuman
And I live my life with a smile
Senyuman...
Smile...
Aku pasti bisa,
I can definitely do it,
Menikmati semua dan menghadapinya...
Enjoying it all and facing it...
Aku yakin pasti bisa...
I'm sure I can do it...
Dan ku jalani hidupku dengan senyuman...
And I'll live my life with a smile...
Oh... あれ?
Oh... What?
Ruangannya kok... beda, ya?
Why is this room... different?
[Answer honestly: What's your hobby?]
Eh? 寝ること。
Eh? Sleeping.
[Answer honestly: What's your other hobby?]
Emang dia tahu kalau aku bohong?
Does it even know if I'm lying?
Bodo amat... ah... 寝ること。
Whatever... ah... sleeping.
[Answer honestly: What's your other hobby?]
Jangan nanya hal yang sama terus, dong!
Stop asking the same thing!
さっきから同じじゃん!
It's been the same thing for a while!
Hobiku tidur. 眠るの大好き。
My hobby is sleeping. I love sleeping.
[Answer honestly: What's your other hobby?]
Ini bercanda, ya? 冗談でしょ、これ?
Is this a joke? This is a joke, right?
Hobiku itu nggak jawab pertanyaan yang sama terus-menerus.
My hobby is not answering the same questions over and over again.
同じ質問に何回も答えないのが趣味。
Not answering the same question multiple times is my hobby.
[Answer honestly: What's your other hobby?]
Hadah, bisa nggak sih buka aja pintunya? Udah cukup, ah.
Ugh, can't you just open the door? I've had enough.
もういいから、早くドア開けてくれない?
Enough already, won't you hurry and open the door?
Nggak. Aku nggak mau jawab。
No. I don't want to answer.
いや、答えない。
No, I won't answer.
Dahlah.
Fine.
まぁ、いいわ。
Well, fine.
[How many steering wheels do you need if you have your own Raft?]
Oh! Akhirnya pertanyaannya beda! Gampang lagi!
Oh! Finally a different question! And an easy one too!
やっと違う質問! しかも簡単!
Finally a different question! And it's easy!
8! Tentu saja 8!
Eight! Of course it's eight!
8! 8 に決まってるでしょ!
Eight! It's obviously eight!
広い宇宙の 数ある一つ
In this vast universe, just one of many
青い地球の 広い世界で
In this wide world on the blue Earth
小さな恋の思いは届く
My small feelings of love reach out
小さな島の あなたの元へ
To where you are, on a small island
あなたと出会い 時は流れる
Meeting you, time flows by
思いを込めた 手紙も増える
The letters filled with feelings increase
いつしか二人 互いに響く
Before I knew it, we both resonate
時に激しく 時に切なく
Sometimes intensely, sometimes painfully
響くは遠く はるか彼方へ
Resonating far, far away
優しい歌は 世界を変える
A gentle song changes the world
ほら あなたにとって大事な人ほど
Look, the more important someone is to you
すぐそばにいるの
The closer they are by your side
ただ あなたにだけ届いてほしい
I just want it to reach only you
響け恋の歌
Let this love song ring out
ほら...
Look...
響け恋の歌
Let this love song ring out
あなたは気づく 二人は歩く
You realize that we both walk
暗い道でも 日々照らす月
Even on dark roads, the moon shines daily
握りしめた手 離すことなく
Holding hands tightly, never letting go
思いは強く 永遠誓う
Feelings grow strong, swearing for eternity
永遠の淵 きっと僕は言う
At the edge of eternity, I'm sure I'll say
思い変わらず 同じ言葉を
The same words, with feelings unchanged
それでも足りず 涙に変わり
Even then it's not enough, turning into tears
喜びになり 言葉にできず
Turning into joy, unable to be put into words
ただ抱きしめる
I just hold you close
ほら あなたにとって大事な人ほど
Look, the more important someone is to you
すぐそばにいるの
The closer they are by your side
ただ あなたにだけ届いてほしい
I just want it to reach only you
響け恋 of 歌
Let this love song ring out
ほら...
Look...
響け恋の歌
Let this love song ring out
夢ならば覚めないで
If it's a dream, don't wake me up
あなたと過ごした時 永遠の星となる
The time I spent with you will become an eternal star
ほら あなたにとって大事な人ほど
Look, the more important someone is to you
すぐそばにいるの
The closer they are by your side
ただ あなたにだけ届いてほしい
I just want it to reach only you
ひびけこいのうた
Let this love song resound
ほら
Listen
あなたにとって
The one for you...
だいじなひとほどすぐそばにいるの
...to care about is right beside you
ただ
I just...
あなたにだけとどいてほしい
...want this to reach only you
ひびけこいのうた
Let this love song resound
ほら
Listen
ひびけこいのうた
Let this love song resound
REPEAT AFTER ME 10 TIMES
[Title: REPEAT AFTER ME 10 TIMES]
Eh? Ngulang apaan?
Eh? Repeat what?
Chaos
[Text: Chaos]
Chaos?
Kepalaku memang lagi chaos sih, tapi maksudnya?
My head is indeed chaotic, but what do you mean?
Meja murid ada 5, terus meja gurunya ada 1...
Five student desks and one teacher desk...
Aku nggak paham.
I don't get it.
Hmm... chaos.
え？
Eh?
ハコス・ベールズ？
Hakos Baelz?
Jangan-jangan maksudnya itu?
Could that be what it means?
JOONN MY SOULLL!! JOONN MY SOULLL!!
Kok pintunya nggak kebuka? Kenapa nggak bisa?
Why isn't the door opening? Why can't I?
Oh! 10 Kali! Oh, maksudnya itu!
Oh! 10 times! Oh, that's what it means!
Okay, Joon My Soul, 10 times.
Eh, kayaknya bukan gitu, deh.
Eh, it's probably not like that.
Joon my soul! Joon my soul! Joon my soul! Joon my soul! Joon my soul! Joon my soul! Joon my soul! Joon my soul! Joon my soul! Joon my soul!
Nice.
Wanna be the biggest dreamer
全速力で未来も現在（いま）も駆け抜けろ
Running full speed through both the future and the present
そう、僕は気づいたんだ
That's right, I've realized it
ずっと宿題忘れてた
I forgot to do my homework for a long time
それはひとつの謎•謎•謎
That's one puzzle, puzzle, puzzle
「僕は誰なんだろう？」
"Who am I?"
スライディングして すりむけたヒザ
Even if I slide and skin my knees
痛くたってね
Even if it hurts
すぐ立ち上がらなきゃ チャンスは逃げてゆく
I've gotta stand right back up, or else my chance will run away
分かってるさ
I know
Big and bigger, biggest dreamer!
夢見るコトがすべてはじまり
Dreaming is the start of everything
それが答えだろ
That's the answer
誰より遠くへ飛んで見せるよ
I'll fly farther than anyone
すべての 明日（あす）を貫いて
Through all the tomorrows
地平線までとんでゆけ
Fly to the horizon
羽をもらった勇気たち
Our courage has gained wings
強く大きくなるために
In order to grow big and strong
僕も走り出そう
I'll run too
聞こえていたよカウントダウン
I've heard the countdown
ずっと前から
For a long time
準備はできてるさ今すぐはじめよう
I'm prepared, let's start now
ゼロに変われ！
Change into zero!
Big and bigger, biggest dreamer!
信じられなきゃ瞬きしてるせつなに消えるよ
If we can't believe, we'll disappear into the twinkling instant
ココロの標的逸らさず走れ
I'll run, not turning away from my heart's target
すべてのチカラぶつけよう
And strike with all my power
Big and bigger, biggest dreamer!
夢見るコトがすべてはじまり
Dreaming is the start of everything
それが答えだろ
That's the answer
誰より遠くへ飛んで見せるよ
I'll fly farther than anyone
すべての 明日（あす）を貫いて
Through all the tomorrows
Bigger and Bigger, bigger streamer
夢見るきことが全て始まり
Dreaming is where it all begins
それが答えだろう
That must be the answer
誰より遠くへ飛んでみせるよ
I'll show you I can fly further than anyone
全ての明日を貫いて
Piercing through every tomorrow
Bigger and Bigger, bigger streamer
夢見るきことが全て始まり
Dreaming is where it all begins
それが答えだろう
That must be the answer
Wanna be the biggest streamer
全速力で
At full speed
未来も今も駆け抜けろ
Run through the future and the now
Bomb?! 爆弾！
Bomb?!
Buset, ini sih bener-bener udah keterlaluan.
Geez, this is really getting out of hand.
Harusnya sekarang aku lagi 3D Showcase,
I was supposed to be doing my 3D Showcase now,
tapi malah nyasar...
but instead I got lost...
terjebak di ruangan yang ada bomnya, terus disuruh mecahin kode morse.
trapped in a room with a bomb, and told to solve Morse code.
Hari ini apes banget!
What a fabulous day!
Terus ada hape juga?
And a phone too?
Aku harus ngapain? Telepon YAGOO terus bilang aku nyasar dan perlu bantuan?
What should I do? Call YAGOO and tell him I'm lost and need help?
Kayaknya aku tahu harus ngapain!
Wait, I think I know what to do!
Ha, halo?
Ha, hello?
Aku nyasar, terjebak, terus ada bom juga.
I'm lost, trapped, and there's a bomb too.
Apa?
What?
Kalau Kamu nggak bisa mecahin kode morse, bisa mampus aku.
I hope you can solve a Morse code or it's so over.
Hah?
Dash dot dash, dot dot dot dot, dot dash, dash dash, dash dash dash, dash dot, dash dot dash, dot dash.
Dash-dot-dash, dot-dot-dot-dot, dot-dash, dash-dash, dash-dash-dash, dash-dot, dash-dot-dash, dot-dash.
C... H... A...
Cepetan! Bomnya mau meledak!
Fast! It's gonna explode!
Bisa ulangin lagi nggak?
Can you repeat again?
Dash dot dash, dot dot dot dot, dot dash, dash dash, dash dash dash, dash dot, dash dot dash, dot dash.
Dash-dot-dash, dot-dot-dot-dot, dot-dash, dash-dash, dash-dash-dash, dash-dot, dash-dot-dash, dot-dash.
M... O... N... uhm...
Chamon apaan coba?
What is Chamon?
Jadi aku bisa mampus beneran.
I think I'm gonna die.
Kayakanya yang terakhir Y... A...
I think the last one is Y... A...
Chamonya? Apaan itu?
Chamonya? What?
Aku nggak tahu kamu ngapain, tapi semoga berhasil!
I don't know what you're doing, but good luck!
Makasih! Bye!
Thanks! Bye!
Cha, Chamonya... Chachamonya?
Chachamonya?
I really want to be with you
I really want to really want to be with you
You're my love, you're my shine, you're my dear
So trust me, trust me, trust me yeah
そばにいるから
Because I'm by your side
ここに僕がいるから
Because I'm right here
Trust me もう何も恐れないで
Trust me, don't be afraid of anything anymore
My dear 見えない糸で
My dear, with an invisible thread
Trust me 繋がっているから
Trust me, because we're connected
ただ感じていてこのぬくもり
Just feel this warmth
ちゃんと聞こえている
I can hear it clearly
君の心の声
The voice of your heart
小さな不安さえ
Even the smallest anxieties
僕が脱ぎ捨ててあげる
I will cast them all away for you
何度も伝えたい
I want to tell you again and again
君はひとりじゃない
That you are not alone
変わることのない
Unchanging as it is
愛はきっとここにある
Love is surely right here
泣いてみればいい
It's okay to cry
頼ってみればいい
It's okay to lean on me
その全てを受け止めると決めた
I've decided to accept all of it
I'm here どこにいたって
I'm here, no matter where you are
一つになれる
We can become one
Trust me この想い解けないから
Trust me, because these feelings won't unravel
My dear 抱えた荷物
My dear, the burdens you carry
Trust me 下ろしてみればいい
Trust me, just try setting them down
そう君のために僕がいるんだ
Yes, I am here just for you
Really want to be with you
Trust me, trust me, trust me yeah
どれほどの悲しみ
Just how much sadness
君は隠してたの
Were you hiding away?
どれほどの想いを
Just how many feelings
胸に閉じ込めてきたの
Have you kept locked in your heart?
痛みと引き換えに
In exchange for that pain
手に入れた強さを
The strength you've gained
いつか優しさへ
Will surely turn into kindness
君は変えてゆけるはず
One day soon, I know it
奪われたって
Even if things are taken away
壊されたって
Even if things are broken
大事なのは君らしくいること
The only thing that matters is being yourself
I'm here たとえ世界が
I'm here, even if the world
終わるとしても
Were to come to an end
Trust me 繋ぐ手を離さないから
Trust me, I will never let go of your hand
Trust me
未来へ歩き出そう
walk into the future,
そう君のために僕がいるんだ
I exist for your sake.
I'm here そばにいるから Call me
I'm here, I'm right next to you, Call me.
僕がいるから Trust me
I'm here, Trust me.
もう何も恐れないで My dear
Trust me, there's nothing to be afraid of, my dear.
見えない糸で Trust me
An invisible thread, Trust me,
繋がっているから
is what connects us.
ただ感じていてこのぬくもり
So feel my warmth by your side.
いつまでもそばにいる Forever
Always by your side, Forever.
密まっても離れない Never ever
No matter what, never letting go, Never ever.
君がいれば Whatever you do
As long as you're here, whatever you do.
ねえ僕に教えて Whatever you say
Hey, tell me, whatever you say.
辛いことあれば全て飲み込み
If there are painful things, swallow them all.
もしそれでも無理ならば Call me call me
If you still can't handle it, Call me, call me.
You're my love, you're my shine, you're my dear
世界的に回しても Trust me
Even if the world turns against you, Trust me.
泣いてみればいい 頼ってみればいい
Don't hesitate to cry and rely on me.
その全てを受け止めると決めた
I decided long ago to accept all your burdens.
I'm here どこにいたって Call me
I'm here, wherever you are, Call me.
一つになれる Trust me
We'll be together, Trust me.
この想い解けないから My dear
These feelings for you will never change, My dear.
抱えた荷物 Trust me
Those things you're carrying, Trust me,
降ろしてみればいい
just put them down.
そう君のために僕がいるんだ
I exist for your sake.
I'm here そばにいるから Call me
I'm here, I'm right next to you, Call me.
僕がいるから Trust me
I'm here, Trust me.
もう何も恐れないで My dear
Trust me, there's nothing to be afraid of, My dear.
見えない糸で Trust me
An invisible thread, Trust me,
繋がっているから
is what connects us.
ただ感じていてこのぬくもり
So feel my warmth by your side.
With me もう離れないで
With me, don't leave me.
Give me その心を開いて
Give me, open your heart.
Fill me 全てを伝えて
Fill me, tell me everything.
With me 言葉はいらない
With me, words are not needed.
Give me 見つめ合えばいい
Give me, just looking at each other is enough.
Feel me 全てを受け取って
Feel me, take everything.
Trust me yeah baby ooh...
ハロー？ 誰かいますか？
Hello...? Anybody here?
ホラゲーは結構やってきたけど、何だろうな...
I have played enough horror games and I don't know why...
これ、すごい既視感ある。
...but it reminds me of something similar.
読みます、これ？ 読むか...
Should I read this? Maybe...
何が目的ですか 何でいるんですか
What is your purpose? Why are you here?
切れてますか 怒ってますか
Are you upset? Are you angry?
ここにいていいですか 戻ります
Is it okay for me to be here? I'm going back.
帰りましょうか 戻ろうか
Shall we go home? Shall we turn back?
何すればいい 何か手伝えますか
What should I do? Can I help with anything?
敵はありますか 何者ですか
Is there an enemy? Who are you?
どこにいますか 近くにいますか
Where are you? Are you nearby?
出てきて アピールしてください
Come out. Please show yourself.
もしもし
Hello?
あのドア、さっき入ったときのと似てるけど...
That door looks similar to the entrance door...
まさか出口？
Is that the exit?
それとも罠？
Or is that a trap?
ホラゲーだったら...
Well, if this is a horror game...
叫んでみたほうがいいのかな？
...should I try to scream?
ああああああああ！！！！
AAAAAAAAHHHHHHHH!!!!
黙れ！
Shut up!
え？
Eh?
どれほどの悲しみ君は隠してたの
How much sadness have you been hiding?
どれほどの思いを胸に閉じ込めてきたの
How much of your feelings have you shut in your chest?
痛みと引き換えに手に入れた強さを
The strength exchanged for the pain,
いつか優しさへ君は変えてゆけるはず
you should be able to turn it into gentleness one day.
誰かの期待にずっと応え
Always responding to someone's expectations,
褒められるのが好きなのですか
do you like being praised?
なりたい自分をすり替えても
Even if you replace the self you want to be,
笑顔はいつでも素敵ですか
is your smile always wonderful?
始まりだけ 夢見て起きる
Only in the beginning, waking up from a dream,
その先なら いつか自分の腕で
eventually, beyond that, with your own arms...
そう大事なものはいつも 形のないもの
Yes, important things are always formless things.
形のないものだけ...
Only the things without form...
手に入れても なくしても 気付かぬまま
whether I obtain them or lose them, I don't even notice.
そうだ 大事な物は いつも
That's right, the important things are always
形のないものだけ
only the things without form,
手に入れても なくしても 気付かぬまま
whether I obtain them or lose them, I don't even notice.
もう一回
One more time
強引なほど 勝ち取き
Seizing victory with brute force,
頭ごなしな 説教だけ
and only preaching with an overbearing attitude.
自暴自棄に 羅列が 凝って
A list of reckless acts piling up,
傷つけながら すぐに尖って
getting sharp while hurting others.
新しい風 味方につけて
Winning over the new wind,
探しているんだ いつか
I'm searching for it someday...
青い鳥を
the blue bird.
そうだ 大事な物は いつも
That's right, the important things are always
形のないものだけ
only the things without form,
手に入れても なくしても 気付かぬまま
whether I obtain them or lose them, I don't even notice.
そうさ 悲しみを 優しさに
That's it, turn sadness into kindness,
自分らしさを 力に
turn your true self into strength,
迷いながらでもいい 歩き出して
it's okay to lose your way, just start walking.
涙の跡は なぜか 吹き切ってた
Somehow, the traces of tears were swept away,
空に虹が出るように 自然なこと
as natural as a rainbow appearing in the sky.
雨はあがった だから
The rain has stopped, so...
そうだ 大事な物は いつも
That's right, the important things are always
形のないものだけ
only the things without form,
手に入れても なくしても 気付かぬまま
whether I obtain them or lose them, I don't even notice.
そうさ 悲しみを 優しさに
That's it, turn sadness into kindness,
自分らしさを 力に
turn your true self into strength,
君ならきっとやれる 信じていて
you can surely do it, believe in yourself.
もう一回
One more time
小さな頃には 宝の地図が
When I was small, a treasure map
頭の中に浮かんでいて
used to float in my head.
いつでも探した 奇跡の場所
I was always searching for that place of miracles,
知らない誰かに 負けないように
so as not to lose to anyone I didn't know.
ララララ... 今では
La-la-la-la... And now,
誇りだらけの毎日
every day is covered in dust.
いつの日か 全ての
Someday, I'll just surrender
時に身を任せるだけ
everything to time.
もしも世界が変わるのなら
If the world were to change,
何も知らない頃の私に
then for the me who knew nothing back then,
触れていて思い出が色褪せないように
keep holding on so that the memories don't fade away.
小さな頃から
From the time I was small,
歌を歌って
I sang songs.
夢見る心
My dreaming heart,
温めてた
I was warming it up.
みんなで真似した
The secret melody
秘密のメロディ
we all imitated together.
今度は遠くに
So that this time,
聞こえるように
it can be heard far away.
もしも時代が 戻るのなら
If the era were to return,
涙を知った 頃の私に
to myself back when I first knew tears,
連れていって 切なさが
take me there, so the sadness...
追いつかないように
won't catch up to me.
もしも世界が 変わるのなら
If the world were to change,
何も知らない 頃の私に
to myself back when I knew nothing,
連れていって 思い出が
take me there, so the memories...
色褪せないように
won't ever fade away.
連れていって 切なさが
Take me there, so the sadness...
追いつかないように
won't catch up to me.
Kenapa semuanya terasa nyata banget?
Why does everything feel so real?
Apa aku nyata?
Am I real?
Apa orang lain bisa ngerasain keberadaanku?
Can others feel my existence?
Is this what déjà vu looks like?
Bukannya sudah biasa?
Isn't it already usual?
Ditikam oleh kecewa
Stabbed by disappointment
Dahlah saja
Just let it go
Oh dahlah saja
Oh, just let it go
Wanna be the Biggest Dreamer
小さな頃から 歌を歌って
From the time I was small, I sang songs
悲しみをやさしさに
Turning sadness into kindness
All these memories mean the world to me.
Thank you for walking this journey with me.
Let's make more! :3
Like! comments! share! subscribe!